# JORDAN "JJ" CARDENAS

Woodinville, WA

Phone: 425-922-3350 | Email: jj@jjcardenas.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jordanjcardenas | GitHub: github.com/cardeens

Portfolio: www.jjcardenas.com

## **SUMMARY**

Recent graduate of an intensive full stack development program backed by five years as a marketing professional in the technology industry. Dedicated, personable, fast learner seeking an entry-level frontend developer role where I can combine my marketing knowledge with my new-found technical skills to help reach millions by building the next great experience.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: ReactJS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Java, Node.js, Bootstrap, Material-UI,

Handlebars.js, Express, MERN Stack **Databases:** MySQL, MongoDB

Deployment & Version Control: Git, Heroku, GoDaddy

#### **PROJECTS**

## Quiz Panda | https://github.com/sali6798/quiz-panda | https://guizpanda.herokuapp.com/

Simple and responsive application that allows users to create surveys and quizzes and share them with friends via email to see who can get the highest score

- Participated with a team of four in all phases of the development life cycle, focusing on coding, testing, and debugging
- Completed the application in less than one week collaborating remotely using Zoom and Slack and presented to class & instructors
- Front end developer: brainstormed the overall the user experience and built out the front-end code with Handlebars, JavaScript, HTML, and Foundation CSS package
- Awards: Best App Overall, Best UI

## MGR | https://github.com/sali6798/mgr-react | https://mgr-talent.herokuapp.com/

Marketing automation tool targeted to the music industry to help record label staff manage social media efforts for their artists

- Two-week team project with agile approach and remote SCRUM meetings
- Front end developer: built out front end experience with React and Material-UI
- Implemented Node packages such as Nodemailer, Express, BCrypt, Uniqid doteny, and Cron
- Thoroughly documented all code changes through a front-end and back-end repository in GitHub to follow versioning best practices
- Awards: Best UI

#### Google Books | github.com/cardeens/googlebooks | ji-googlebooksfinal.herokuapp.com

Responsive application that uses the Google Books API to search for books and allows users to save or remove titles from their Saved list

- Built individually using MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js) and routed search queries from Google Books API
- Thorough testing, troubleshooting, and debugging across front and back end code to create functional and responsive application
- Deployed final application through Heroku and have continued to push continuous improvements

## FINDR | https://github.com/cardeens/FindrApp | https://cardeens.github.io/FindrApp/index.html

Simple and user-friendly application that randomly displays an image from a restaurant in a card that can be cycled through until an appealing option is picked. Once the top choice is chosen, the restaurant information will be shown to get a user to their food as fast as possible

- Initially worked in a team of four in a one-week period to develop, debug, and deploy application using the Zomato and Google Maps APIs on the back end and Bootstrap to format the front end
- After the program, individually took initiative and updated the app to use Yelp Fusion API in an effort to continuously improve the app and provide the best possible user experience

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Marketing Strategy Consultant** July 2019 - March 2020

Lenati LLC Seattle, WA

Worked independently across key account such as Microsoft, T-Mobile, and Vans to drive several successful, high-visibility marketing and program management projects Key Accomplishments:

- Led content reviews for Microsoft Ignite presentations with engineering and product subject matter experts and ultimately achieved the highest satisfaction rating across business groups
- Set and surpassed target goal of Pluralsight training modules pushed to production while acting as a project manager and successfully eliminating roadblocks, presenting progress to managers, and identifying technical and business requirements

Sr. Marketing Specialist March 2016 - July 2019

Bellevue, WA Xevo Inc.

Collaborated cross-functionally in a fast-faced, ambiguous startup environment to support and lead marketing programs and product development efforts Kev Accomplishments:

- Demonstrated ability to learn quickly, work both independently and in teams, and analyze data to deliver on client requests and meet deadlines for co-marketing activities
- Applied critical thinking and worked with UX team to research best possible user experience for new cutting-edge applications that aligned with business requirements
- Worked with senior leadership to rebrand company and build out new web, print, and video content to support the company's new vision and brand

**Account Executive** July 2015 – February 2016

**Digital Intelligence Systems** Kirkland, WA

Eagerly took on key ownership to manage accounts within the high-tech industry vertical, namely Microsoft and Facebook

Key Accomplishments:

Proactively built trusting and personable relationships with hiring managers at client sites by building an understanding of team needs and setting goals for client success

## VOLUNTEER

Social Media Strategist July 2016 - March 2019

**HERE Seattle** Seattle, WA

Led marketing programs and community engagement efforts on the leadership team for a non-profit dedicated to supporting an inclusive culture in technology and making a positive impact in the Seattle community

## **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Development Certificate: University of Washington, Seattle, WA May 2020

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in ReactJS, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

BA in Business Administration, Marketing Major: Seattle University, Seattle, WA

Dean's List for Albers School of Business and Economics (Fall 2013-Spring 2015)